<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>social-justice on R-Ladies</title>
    <link>/tags/social-justice/</link>
    <description>Recent content in social-justice on R-Ladies</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/social-justice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>#BlackLivesMatter: A joint statement by Forwards and R-Ladies</title>
      <link>/post/blm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/blm/</guid>
      <description>As organizations committed to broadening diversity and inclusion in our community, we stand with #BlackLivesMatter and join those who demand justice for systemic oppression. Pervasive racism negatively impacts the participation of Black people in society. The current events in the USA echo what has happened and continues to happen to minoritised people across the world. We are aggregating resources and are taking deliberate actions to amplify the voices of Black, Indigenous and People of Color in the R community now and moving forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#BlackLivesMatters : une déclaration commune de Forwards et R-Ladies</title>
      <link>/post/blm_fr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/blm_fr/</guid>
      <description>En tant qu’organisations dédiées à augmenter la diversité et l’intégration de tous dans nos communautés, nous soutenons #BlackLivesMatter et rejoignons ceux qui demandent justice face à l’oppression systémique. Le racisme omniprésent affecte négativement la participation de personnes noires dans notre société. Les événements en cours aux États-Unis font écho à ce qui s’est produit et continue de se produire pour les personnes marginalisées (ou réduites à être des minorités) à travers le monde.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#VidasNegrasImportam: Uma declaração conjunta de Forwards e R-Ladies</title>
      <link>/post/blm_pt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/blm_pt/</guid>
      <description>Como organizações comprometidas em ampliar a diversidade e a inclusão em nossa comunidade, apoiamos o movimento #BlackLivesMatter ou #VidasNegrasImportam e nos unimos a quem exige justiça frente a opressão sistêmica. O racismo generalizado afeta negativamente a participação das pessoas negras na sociedade. Os eventos atuais nos EUA ecoam o que aconteceu e continua acontecendo com pessoas que fazem parte de minorias em todo o mundo. Estamos agregando recursos e adotando ações deliberadas para amplificar as vozes de pessoas negras, indígenas e de outros grupos não-brancos da comunidade R, agora e no futuro.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#VidasNegrasImportan: Una declaración conjunta de Forwards y R-Ladies</title>
      <link>/post/blm_es/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/blm_es/</guid>
      <description>Como organizaciones comprometidas con la ampliación de la diversidad y la inclusión en nuestra comunidad, apoyamos a #VidasNegrasImportan, #BlackLivesMatter y nos unimos a quienes demandan justicia por la opresión sistémica. El racismo generalizado afecta negativamente la participación de las personas negras en la sociedad. Los eventos actuales en los Estados Unidos hacen eco de lo que sucedió y continúa sucediendo a las personas minoritarias en todo el mundo.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
