<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2018 on R-Ladies</title>
    <link>/tags/2018/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2018 on R-Ladies</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/2018/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>vacaciones &lt;- crecer(RedRLadies)</title>
      <link>/post/vacaciones_crecer_redrladies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/vacaciones_crecer_redrladies/</guid>
      <description>Nos gustaría contarles cómo unas vacaciones llevaron al crecimiento de la comunidad R-Ladies en América del Sur. La historia involucra múltiples países y encuentros en el momento adecuado de la vida.
Mine Dogucu Soy de Turquía pero viví en Estados Unidos la mayor parte de mi edad adulta. En diciembre de 2014, decidí viajar a Sudamérica, a conocer Chile, Uruguay y Argentina. Como era estudiante de postgrado en ese momento tuve que buscar formas de reducir los costos del viaje.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What happened in 2018?</title>
      <link>/post/what-happened-in-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/what-happened-in-2018/</guid>
      <description> Retrospective 2018  Include IWD 2018 R-Ladies growth LatinR Conferences Blog posts   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vacation &lt;- grow(RLadiesNetwork)</title>
      <link>/post/vacation_grow_rladiesnetwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/vacation_grow_rladiesnetwork/</guid>
      <description>We would like to tell you how one vacation lead to growth of R Ladies community in South America. The story involves multiple countries and crossing paths at the right time in life.
Mine Dogucu I am from Turkey but I lived in the United States most of my adulthood. In December 2014, I decided to take a trip to South America - to Chile, Uruguay, and Argentina.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3. Behind the scenes of R-Ladies IWD2018 Twitter action!</title>
      <link>/post/conclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/conclusion/</guid>
      <description>As told by Page and Sheila On March the 8th, International Women’s Day, we ran a continuous feed of awesome R-Ladies profiles from our directory via [@rladies_iwd2018](https://twitter.com/rladies_iwd2018). It was a blast! And a lot of team work too! To round out our three-part blog series of the IWD Directory campaign, we’ll discuss topics related to privacy law, contact information collection and the future of our R-Ladies directory project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2. Behind the scenes of R-Ladies IWD2018 Twitter action!</title>
      <link>/post/deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/deployment/</guid>
      <description>As told by Kelly O’Briant On March the 8th, International Women’s Day, we ran a continuous feed of awesome R-Ladies profiles from our directory via @rladies_iwd2018. It was a blast! And a lot of team work too! In this blog post, we’ll cover the deployment and monitoring stages of our project. You can also read the Part 1.
 Recap The great part about being put in charge of deploying a project, is that all the hard work is mostly done already!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1. Behind the scenes of R-Ladies IWD2018 Twitter action!</title>
      <link>/post/ideation_and_creation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ideation_and_creation/</guid>
      <description>As told by Maëlle Salmon with notes from Bea Hernández On March the 8th, International Women’s Day, we ran a continuous feed of awesome R-Ladies profiles from our directory via @rladies_iwd2018. It was a blast! And a lot of team work too! In this blog post, we’ll explain how we designed and completed our Twitter action.
 An idea sown on IWD2017! Last year on International Women’s day, R-Ladies ally David Robinson promoted Twitter accounts of female data scientists.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
