<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Activities on R-Ladies Global</title><link>https://rladies-dev.netlify.app/activities/</link><description>Recent content in Activities on R-Ladies Global</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://rladies-dev.netlify.app/activities/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blogs by R-Ladies</title><link>https://rladies-dev.netlify.app/activities/rladies-blogs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rladies-dev.netlify.app/activities/rladies-blogs/</guid><description>Curated list of awesome blogs by R-Ladies, inspired by
Poll #1 results are in! Now let’s see if we can answer this *for real* by generating an✨ AWESOME✨ list of #RLadies blogs! 💜 Comment 👇🏽 for yourself or someone you know (1 comment = 1 blog)! I’ll kick it off w/ some #RLadies blogs I have read recently!https://t.co/9YPD23OwqC
&amp;mdash; We are R-Ladies (@WeAreRLadies) February 17, 2021 The list lives in its own GitHub Repo, and you are very welcome to add your own!</description></item><item><title>Coordinated by the Global Team</title><link>https://rladies-dev.netlify.app/activities/gt-coordinated/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rladies-dev.netlify.app/activities/gt-coordinated/</guid><description>The majority of work for R-Ladies is done by the excellent chapter organisers around the world. For this, R-Ladies as a global organisation helps with technical infrastructure and a network the organisers can rely on for help and guidance if they need it.
In addition, the Global team coordinates activities that span all chapters. These activities ensure the chapter and R-Ladies around the world can access the international network and aid that exists for the community.</description></item><item><title>Events</title><link>https://rladies-dev.netlify.app/activities/events/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rladies-dev.netlify.app/activities/events/</guid><description/></item><item><title>International Womens Day Campaigns</title><link>https://rladies-dev.netlify.app/activities/iwd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rladies-dev.netlify.app/activities/iwd/</guid><description>R-Ladies Global has coordinated International Women Day actions to encourage more people from gender minorities to participate in the community on Twitter and to promote people in the community. The coordinators of these campaigns have written blog posts about them, which you can find links to below.
Acción de Twitter para el IWD 2019Como cada 8 de marzo, una vez más se celebra el Día Internacional de la Mujer (IWD/8M).</description></item><item><title>Mentoring program</title><link>https://rladies-dev.netlify.app/activities/mentoring/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rladies-dev.netlify.app/activities/mentoring/</guid><description>Never worry, there is always an R-Lady mentor to walk with you!
The main objective of the R-Ladies Mentoring Program is to help organisers conduct successful meetups and keep their chapters active.
Organizing an R-Ladies chapter involves a series of tasks that can feel overwhelming to a new organiser. However, a number of experienced R-Ladies organisers are willing to mentor new ones and provide some great advice.
For mentors, this is an opportunity to help build the community, learn about the realities of other chapters, gain experience as a mentor, and contributing to R-Ladies&amp;rsquo; goals.</description></item><item><title>Twitter campaigns</title><link>https://rladies-dev.netlify.app/activities/twitter-campaigns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rladies-dev.netlify.app/activities/twitter-campaigns/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>