<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>R-Ladies Global</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/</link><description>Recent content on R-Ladies Global</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.rladies.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>R-consortium</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/home/sponsors/rconsortium/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/home/sponsors/rconsortium/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Happy 23rd Birthday R!</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2023-02-28/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2023-02-28/</guid><description/></item><item><title>New R-Ladies Website</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/news/news/2023-02-22-new-r-ladies-website/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/news/news/2023-02-22-new-r-ladies-website/</guid><description>&lt;p>We are thrilled to announce the release of our new R-Ladies website!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been a long journey, with many people involved, and we are happy to be able to finally share with you this new site and some new content.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>R-Ladies Vitória: Use of R for Public Policy Decisions on Maternal and Child Health in Brazil</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2023-02-09/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2023-02-09/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Learning the Fundamentals of R, Workshop with R-Ladies Gaborone and Botswana R User Group</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2022-12-12/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2022-12-12/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Global Leadership Team Transition</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/news/2022-11-18-global-leadership-team-transition/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/news/2022-11-18-global-leadership-team-transition/</guid><description>R-Ladies first began as a meet-up in 2012, and became a global organization in 2016. Since inception, the R-Ladies Global organization has been run on 100% volunteer effort from individuals and chapters throughout the world. The organization is built upon layers of support - the global leadership team, the broader global team, local chapter organizers, and community members - all who donate their time and effort to sustain the mission of promoting gender diversity in the R community.</description></item><item><title>R-Ladies Taipei Hopes to Host Hybrid Events in the Future</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2022-08-23/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2022-08-23/</guid><description/></item><item><title>R Ladies Philly is Making a Difference with its Annual Datathon Focused on Local Issues</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2022-07-26/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2022-07-26/</guid><description/></item><item><title>R Ladies Santa Rosa Leading with Other R Communities in Latin America to Create More Accessibility</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2022-07-14/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2022-07-14/</guid><description/></item><item><title>R Ladies Cuernavaca Partners with Biotechnology Institute to Quickly Expand Reach in 2022</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2022-07-07/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2022-07-07/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Virtual Events Opened New Horizons for R-Ladies Dallas</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2022-07-05/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2022-07-05/</guid><description/></item><item><title>R-Ladies Cotonou Talks About Running an R users Group in Benin, West Africa</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2022-06-06/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2022-06-06/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Request for Proposal - Javascript Development (Contract Work)</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/news/2022-03-28-request-for-proposal-javascript-development/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/news/2022-03-28-request-for-proposal-javascript-development/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>The R-Ladies global organization wants to implement some new functionalities (using Javascript) for a re-implementation of their website, whose source code may be found on &lt;a href="https://github.com/rladies/website">GitHub&lt;/a>.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>R-Ladies would like to invite you to prepare a proposal to accomplish the above task that includes timeline, cost, and deliverables. The following RFP includes a background of our organization and describes the purpose of the redesign, its desired functionality, and specific requests relating to the proposal. We understand that details may be subject to change upon vendor recommendation and/ or research of more optimal solutions. In your proposal, please feel free to suggest alternatives where noted.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>R-Ladies Galapagos Chapter on Collaborations, Challenges, and Opportunities During the Pandemic</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2022-01-26/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2022-01-26/</guid><description/></item><item><title>R-Ladies Lagos on Data Visualization and Hybrid Events</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2021-12-22/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2021-12-22/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Chile’s R Ladies Group is Open and Inclusive</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2021-11-09/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2021-11-09/</guid><description/></item><item><title>R-Ladies+ Feat. useR! 2021</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/blog/2021-09-24-r-ladies-feat-user-2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/blog/2021-09-24-r-ladies-feat-user-2021/</guid><description>In this post, you will see that we have used the R-Ladies logo with the colors of the rainbow and the trans flags. We have also added a + to the R-Ladies name. As symbols and words matter a lot, we wanted to explicitly communicate, with the use of these symbols, the importance of diversity and inclusion to our community. We used them in this useR! to reinforce that we welcome diversity and put an effort into creating collectively a safe and friendly space.</description></item><item><title>Curating for @WeAreRLadies on Twitter</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/blog/2021-09-23-curating-for-wearerladies-on-twitter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/blog/2021-09-23-curating-for-wearerladies-on-twitter/</guid><description>Figure 1: Photo by Arno Smit on Unsplash (https://unsplash.com/photos/iI72r3gSwWY) This post was originally published on Shannon Pileggi’s personal blog.
TL; DR In February 2021 I tweeted to a daunting &amp;gt;20k followers by curating for @WeAreLadies on Twitter. This was great opportunity to share knowledge, interact with others, and learn something in return, ultimately cultivating new connections and collaborations. From preparation to fruition, I hope this post helps you confidently enroll as a curator!</description></item><item><title>Latin R talks about the Trials of Starting a Conference in Latin America</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2021-07-20-latinr/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2021-07-20-latinr/</guid><description/></item><item><title>R Ladies Montevideo, Uruguay, Explains How to Create a High Quality Conference in the Southern Hemisphere</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2021-07-20-montevideo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2021-07-20-montevideo/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Working with Databases in R – Video Presentation from NairobiR and R-Ladies Nairobi</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2021-06-24/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2021-06-24/</guid><description/></item><item><title>R-Ladies Philly – Building our Online Community During the Pandemic</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2021-05-27/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2021-05-27/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Checking in with R-Ladies Taipei</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2021-05-14/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2021-05-14/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The R-Ladies Mentoring Program: R-Ladies Cotonou journey</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/blog/2021-02-04-cotonout_mentoring/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/blog/2021-02-04-cotonout_mentoring/</guid><description>We are very happy to provide you this blog article in different languages, English, French and Spanish. If you would like to know more about how to contribute to the R-Ladies Blog in general or would like to recommend anything, please reach out to us with an e-mail at christin@rladies.org.
How it all started …? 🤔 R-Ladies Cotonou is a local chapter of R-Ladies Global located in Cotonou, Benin (West Africa).</description></item><item><title>Reduced Service Mode for R-Ladies Global</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/news/2020-11-23-reduced-service-note/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/news/2020-11-23-reduced-service-note/</guid><description>This year has been and continues to be a challenging year for many, if not all, of us.
We have needed to make some adjustments in our personal lives and as R-Ladies is a volunteer run organisation we also needed to make some changes in the work we do at R-Ladies Global.
Since the coronavirus pandemic began, we have added new infrastructure for online meetups via Calendly, Zoom and a YouTube channel, along with guides and training for organizers.</description></item><item><title>Latin American Communities and Organizations: useR!2020</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2020-07-07/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2020-07-07/</guid><description/></item><item><title>#BlackLivesMatter: A joint statement by Forwards and R-Ladies</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/news/2020-06-06-blm/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/news/2020-06-06-blm/</guid><description>As organizations committed to broadening diversity and inclusion in our community, we stand with #BlackLivesMatter and join those who demand justice for systemic oppression. Pervasive racism negatively impacts the participation of Black people in society. The current events in the USA echo what has happened and continues to happen to minoritised people across the world. We are aggregating resources and are taking deliberate actions to amplify the voices of Black, Indigenous and People of Color in the R community now and moving forward.</description></item><item><title>R-Ladies Infrastructure for Online Meetups</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/blog/2020-04-24-online-meetups/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/blog/2020-04-24-online-meetups/</guid><description>Our chapters have cancelled in-person meetups due to the corona virus pandemic. However, we want our members to be able to stay connected and still share their latest R-related discoveries and journeys. To support our chapter organisers in moving their events online, we decided to provide them with video conferencing infrastructure.
Our network has grown to over 160 chapters worldwide so we were wondering how many meeting rooms we would need.</description></item><item><title>Recipe for a year-end video</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/blog/2020-01-27-rladies_video_2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/blog/2020-01-27-rladies_video_2019/</guid><description>To close the awesome R-Ladies 2019 year we made a video, if you haven&amp;rsquo;t seen it yet, here it is:
Happy New Year to all #rladies and allies! 🎉🎉🎉
Video put together by @yabellini &amp;amp; @_lacion_ , voice @AlejaBellini 💜💜💜 pic.twitter.com/QRxuJxLugj
&amp;mdash; R-Ladies Global (@RLadiesGlobal) January 1, 2020 Did you like it? Do you want to know how we did it? Here we will give you all the details:
What story are we going to tell?</description></item><item><title>Gabriela de Queiroz steps down from the R-Ladies Global Leadership Team</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/news/2019-12-18-gdq-departure/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/news/2019-12-18-gdq-departure/</guid><description>R-Ladies started out as a meetup group in San Francisco, when Gabriela de Queiroz founded the first chapter and organised the first event in 2012. Following this example, three further groups started out over the next three years. Shortly after the useR! conference in 2016, where Gabriela and other organisers met in person, the R-Ladies Global organisation was co-founded by several active community members.
Since then, the number of R-Ladies chapters has grown massively and rapidly.</description></item><item><title>R-Ladies Global's response to the DataCamp Assessment Report</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/news/2019-10-22-datacamp-third-party-review/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/news/2019-10-22-datacamp-third-party-review/</guid><description>DataCamp&amp;rsquo;s CEO Jonathan Cornelissen sexually assaulted an employee by making &amp;ldquo;uninvited physical contact&amp;rdquo; in October 2017. This became public in April 2019, after which we released a statement on our blog. For a comprehensive account of events, please see this article by Davey Alba for BuzzFeed News published in May 2019. DataCamp commissioned a third-party review which has now been released. This blogpost is to add some clarification around references to R-Ladies made in that report.</description></item><item><title>Hoy tenemos más tiempo para entender cómo se están utilizando los modelos de Machine Learning y poder interpretarlos</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2019-10-14/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2019-10-14/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The R-Ladies Revolution</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2019-08-26/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2019-08-26/</guid><description/></item><item><title>How R-Ladies made data science inclusive</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2019-07-24/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2019-07-24/</guid><description/></item><item><title>R community blasts DataCamp response to exec's 'inappropriate behavior'</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2019-04-17/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2019-04-17/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Mujeres que forman redes para lograr un sitio en la ciencia</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2019-04-09/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2019-04-09/</guid><description/></item><item><title>R-Ladies Global's disapproval of DataCamp</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/news/2019-04-08-statement-about-datacamp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/news/2019-04-08-statement-about-datacamp/</guid><description>This blog post is a slightly extended version of the official statement the R-Ladies Global organization made via Twitter, in a form that is easier to share. The views expressed here are the views of the R-Ladies Global Team signing at the end of this post and do not represent the R-Ladies community at large.
Why we condemn DataCamp&amp;rsquo;s handling of sexual assault We are very disappointed by the way DataCamp handled the sexual assault of an employee by a C-level executive.</description></item><item><title>A Multimillion-Dollar Startup Hid A Sexual Harassment Incident By Its CEO — Then A Community of Outsiders Dragged It Into the Light</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2019-05-13/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2019-05-13/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Día de la empleada doméstica. Los números del sector más desprotegido</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2019-04-03-cronista/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2019-04-03-cronista/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Hay que perder ese miedo irracional a las matemáticas</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2019-04-03-innovando/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2019-04-03-innovando/</guid><description/></item><item><title>IWD 2019 Twitter Action</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/blog/2019-03-25-blog_iwdtwitter_2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/blog/2019-03-25-blog_iwdtwitter_2019/</guid><description>Every year on March 8th, the world celebrates International Women&amp;rsquo;s Day (IWD). Although this date has different ways of celebration, it has one point in common - the fight for gender equality. The previous year, in 2018, an enthusiast R-Ladies&amp;rsquo; group took the initiative for a massive project to tweet about all the profiles registered in the R-ladies directory, throughout 8th March 2018. In February this year, the year 2019, Yanina proposed to follow their lead and tweet about all the R-Ladies Chapters, throughout 8th March 2019.</description></item><item><title>What happened in 2018?</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/blog/2018-12-12-what-happened-in-2018/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/blog/2018-12-12-what-happened-in-2018/</guid><description>Retrospective 2018 Include IWD 2018 R-Ladies growth LatinR Conferences Blog posts</description></item><item><title>Las startups españolas necesitan mujeres programadoras: estas iniciativas quieren encontrarlas</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2018-10-31/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2018-10-31/</guid><description/></item><item><title>vacation &lt;- grow(RLadiesNetwork)</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/blog/2018-10-27-vacation_grow_rladiesnetwork/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/blog/2018-10-27-vacation_grow_rladiesnetwork/</guid><description>We would like to tell you how one vacation lead to growth of R Ladies community in South America. The story involves multiple countries and crossing paths at the right time in life.
Mine Dogucu I am from Turkey but I lived in the United States most of my adulthood. In December 2014, I decided to take a trip to South America - to Chile, Uruguay, and Argentina. Being a graduate student at the time put me in a need to lower my travel costs.</description></item><item><title>Why the future isn’t female in computing</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2018-10-22/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2018-10-22/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Programación - La calculadora mágica de los científicos de datos cumple 25 años</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2018-09-07/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2018-09-07/</guid><description/></item><item><title>La calculadora mágica de los científicos de datos cumple 25 años</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2018-08-22/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2018-08-22/</guid><description/></item><item><title>R Generation: 25 Years of R</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2018-08-11/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2018-08-11/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Las mujeres forman redes para lograr un sitio en la ciencia</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2018-06-20/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2018-06-20/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Mujeres programadoras contra los estereotipos: adivina quién va ganando</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2018-07-23/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2018-07-23/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Reciclé mi vida profesional por completo haciendo cursos gratuitos de Coursera sobre data science</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2018-05-28/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2018-05-28/</guid><description/></item><item><title>R-Ladie, la organización que llegó a Mendoza para acercar la tecnología a las mujeres</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2018-05-05/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2018-05-05/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Las ingenieras que luchan para que la inteligencia artificial tenga 'madres'</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2018-04-03/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2018-04-03/</guid><description/></item><item><title>3. Behind the scenes of R-Ladies IWD2018 Twitter action!</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/blog/conclusion/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/blog/conclusion/</guid><description>As told by Page and Sheila On March the 8th, International Women&amp;rsquo;s Day, we ran a continuous feed of awesome R-Ladies profiles from our directory via @rladies_iwd2018. It was a blast! And a lot of team work too! To round out our three-part blog series of the IWD Directory campaign, we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss topics related to privacy law, contact information collection and the future of our R-Ladies directory project. You can also read the Part 1 and Part 2.</description></item><item><title>2. Behind the scenes of R-Ladies IWD2018 Twitter action!</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/blog/deployment/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/blog/deployment/</guid><description>As told by Kelly O&amp;rsquo;Briant On March the 8th, International Women&amp;rsquo;s Day, we ran a continuous feed of awesome R-Ladies profiles from our directory via @rladies_iwd2018. It was a blast! And a lot of team work too! In this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ll cover the deployment and monitoring stages of our project. You can also read the Part 1.
Recap The great part about being put in charge of deploying a project, is that all the hard work is mostly done already!</description></item><item><title>1. Behind the scenes of R-Ladies IWD2018 Twitter action!</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/blog/2018-03-26-ideation_and_creation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/blog/2018-03-26-ideation_and_creation/</guid><description>As told by Maëlle Salmon with notes from Bea Hernández On March the 8th, International Women&amp;rsquo;s Day, we ran a continuous feed of awesome R-Ladies profiles from our directory via @rladies_iwd2018. It was a blast! And a lot of team work too! In this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ll explain how we designed and completed our Twitter action.
An idea sown on IWD2017! Last year on International Women&amp;rsquo;s day, R-Ladies ally David Robinson promoted Twitter accounts of female data scientists.</description></item><item><title>History</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/blog/2018-02-24-history/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/blog/2018-02-24-history/</guid><description>R-Ladies was founded by Gabriela de Queiroz. She wanted to do something to give back to the R learning community after going to several meetups and learning a lot for free. The first meetup took place in San Francisco, California (United States) on October 1, 2012. In the following years two more R-Ladies chapters launched independently around the world : Twin Cities, USA and Taipei. R-Ladies London launched in March 2016.</description></item><item><title>The R community is doing really well in gender diversity</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2018-01-03/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2018-01-03/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Teaching Students To Ask Questions, Take Risks</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2017-12-27/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2017-12-27/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Chica tech - De la economía a la programación, en un abrir y cerrar de ojos</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2017-11-20/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2017-11-20/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Mujeres en la ciencia y la tecnología</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2017-10-14/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2017-10-14/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Women in tech aim to grow next generation's interest beyond family ties</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2017-10-12/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2017-10-12/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ellas programan en uno de los lenguajes más duros del mercado</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2017-08-11/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2017-08-11/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Diferentes na biologia sim. Inferiores não, dizem mulheres na tecnologia</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2017-09-06/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2017-09-06/</guid><description/></item><item><title>El aporte silencioso a la agroinformática</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2017-06-26/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2017-06-26/</guid><description/></item><item><title>La llamada del dato</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2017-05-29-20minutos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2017-05-29-20minutos/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Más mujeres en las competiciones de datos</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/press/2017-05-29-eldiario/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/press/2017-05-29-eldiario/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Blogs by R-Ladies</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/activities/rladies-blogs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/activities/rladies-blogs/</guid><description>Curated list of awesome blogs by R-Ladies, inspired by
Poll #1 results are in! Now let’s see if we can answer this *for real* by generating an✨ AWESOME✨ list of #RLadies blogs! 💜 Comment 👇🏽 for yourself or someone you know (1 comment = 1 blog)! I’ll kick it off w/ some #RLadies blogs I have read recently!https://t.co/9YPD23OwqC
&amp;mdash; We are R-Ladies (@WeAreRLadies) February 17, 2021</description></item><item><title>Code of Conduct</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/coc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/coc/</guid><description>R-Ladies is dedicated to providing a harassment-free experience for everyone. We do not tolerate harassment of participants in any form.
This code of conduct applies to all R-Ladies spaces, including meetups, Twitter, Slack, mailing lists, both online and offline. Anyone who violates this code of conduct may be sanctioned or expelled from these spaces at the discretion of the Global Leadership Team.
Some R-Ladies spaces may have additional rules in place, which will be made clearly available to participants.</description></item><item><title>Coordinated by the Global Team</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/activities/gt-coordinated/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/activities/gt-coordinated/</guid><description>The majority of work for R-Ladies is done by the excellent chapter organisers around the world. For this, R-Ladies as a global organisation helps with technical infrastructure and a network the organisers can rely on for help and guidance if they need it.
In addition, the Global team coordinates activities that span all chapters. These activities ensure the chapter and R-Ladies around the world can access the international network and aid that exists for the community.</description></item><item><title>Directory</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/directory/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/directory/</guid><description>We would love more R-Ladies to appear in our Directory! Please fill out our form! It only takes a few minutes, and soon your profile will be online.
If you want to update your profile just fill the same form and drop us a line in the comment box saying you want to update your profile!
Or you can just email us at speakers[at]rladies[dot]org with any relevant info about yourself – easy!</description></item><item><title>Events</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/activities/events/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/activities/events/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Get Involved</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/about-us/involved/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/about-us/involved/</guid><description>Support your local chapters with venue space and funding for food and beverages. Support your local R-Ladies speakers by inviting them to talk – no excuses for unequal conference speaker ratios. Use the R-Ladies directory. Join the R-Ladies directory . Encourage coding women to be part of R-Ladies. Share code (R-Ladies Global Github). Inspire and support others. Join the community slack. Teach. Blog. Tweet, Retweet and follow @RLadiesGlobal and R-Ladies chapter accounts.</description></item><item><title>History</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/about-us/history/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/about-us/history/</guid><description>Gabriela de Queiroz founded R-Ladies on October 1, 2012. She wanted to give back to the community after going to several meetups and learning a lot for free. The first meetup was placed in San Francisco, California (United States). In the following years two more R-Ladies chapters started around the globe: Twin Cities and Taipei. R-Ladies London was the fourth chapter, which launched in March 2016. Although each chapter started working independently, the need for high-level coordination and support became evident at useR!</description></item><item><title>International Womens Day Campaigns</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/activities/iwd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/activities/iwd/</guid><description>R-Ladies Global has coordinated International Women Day actions to encourage more people from gender minorities to participate in the community on Twitter and to promote people in the community. The coordinators of these campaigns have written blog posts about them, which you can find links to below.
Acción de Twitter para el IWD 2019Como cada 8 de marzo, una vez más se celebra el Día Internacional de la Mujer (IWD/8M).</description></item><item><title>Meet the global team</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/about-us/global-team/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/about-us/global-team/</guid><description>R-ladies Global is run by a volunteer group with designated responsibilities within the organisation. The leadership team has an overarching role, making sure the organisation is well-structured, keeps promises made to sponsors and members, and directs the evolution of R-ladies as a whole.</description></item><item><title>Mentoring program</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/activities/mentoring/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/activities/mentoring/</guid><description>Never worry, there is always an R-Lady mentor to walk with you!
The main objective of the R-Ladies Mentoring Program is to help organisers conduct successful meetups and keep their chapters active.
Organizing an R-Ladies chapter involves a series of tasks that can feel overwhelming to a new organiser. However, a number of experienced R-Ladies organisers are willing to mentor new ones and provide some great advice.
For mentors, this is an opportunity to help build the community, learn about the realities of other chapters, gain experience as a mentor, and contributing to R-Ladies&amp;rsquo; goals.</description></item><item><title>Mission</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/about-us/mission/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/about-us/mission/</guid><description>R-LADIES IS A WORLDWIDE ORGANIZATION WHOSE MISSION IS TO PROMOTE GENDER DIVERSITY IN THE R COMMUNITY.
The R community suffers from an under-representation of minority genders (including but not limited to cis/trans women, trans men, non-binary, genderqueer, agender) in every role and area of participation, whether as leaders, package developers, conference speakers, conference participants, educators, or users (see recent stats).
As a diversity initiative, the mission of R-Ladies is to achieve proportionate representation by encouraging, inspiring, and empowering people of genders currently under-represented in the R community.</description></item><item><title>R-Ladies Directory form</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/directory-update/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/directory-update/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Twitter campaigns</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/activities/twitter-campaigns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/activities/twitter-campaigns/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>