<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>News from the Global Team on R-Ladies Global</title><link>https://--rladies-dev.netlify.app/news/</link><description>Recent content in News from the Global Team on R-Ladies Global</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://--rladies-dev.netlify.app/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Global Team Recruiting</title><link>https://--rladies-dev.netlify.app/news/2023-04-11-global-team-recruiting/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://--rladies-dev.netlify.app/news/2023-04-11-global-team-recruiting/</guid><description>Photo by Hannah Busing on Unsplash. Alt text: Image of arms and hands of women wearing colorful sweaters in a circle with hands piled together.
TL; DR The R-Ladies Global Team is recruiting new members! Please fill this form to submit yourself for consideration.
Background The R-Ladies Global Team is made of volunteers that dedicate a few hours per week to the management of the global organization. We think of ourselves as one larger Global Team comprised of many smaller teams that address specific organizational needs.</description></item><item><title>New R-Ladies Website</title><link>https://--rladies-dev.netlify.app/news/news/2023-02-22-new-r-ladies-website/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://--rladies-dev.netlify.app/news/news/2023-02-22-new-r-ladies-website/</guid><description>&lt;p>We are thrilled to announce the release of our new R-Ladies website!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been a long journey, with many people involved, and we are happy to be able to finally share with you this new site and some new content.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Global Leadership Team Transition</title><link>https://--rladies-dev.netlify.app/news/2022-11-18-global-leadership-team-transition/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://--rladies-dev.netlify.app/news/2022-11-18-global-leadership-team-transition/</guid><description>R-Ladies first began as a meet-up in 2012, and became a global organization in 2016. Since inception, the R-Ladies Global organization has been run on 100% volunteer effort from individuals and chapters throughout the world. The organization is built upon layers of support - the global leadership team, the broader global team, local chapter organizers, and community members - all who donate their time and effort to sustain the mission of promoting gender diversity in the R community.</description></item><item><title>Request for Proposal - Javascript Development (Contract Work)</title><link>https://--rladies-dev.netlify.app/news/2022-03-28-request-for-proposal-javascript-development/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://--rladies-dev.netlify.app/news/2022-03-28-request-for-proposal-javascript-development/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>The R-Ladies global organization wants to implement some new functionalities (using Javascript) for a re-implementation of their website, whose source code may be found on &lt;a href="https://github.com/rladies/website">GitHub&lt;/a>.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>R-Ladies would like to invite you to prepare a proposal to accomplish the above task that includes timeline, cost, and deliverables. The following RFP includes a background of our organization and describes the purpose of the redesign, its desired functionality, and specific requests relating to the proposal. We understand that details may be subject to change upon vendor recommendation and/ or research of more optimal solutions. In your proposal, please feel free to suggest alternatives where noted.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reduced Service Mode for R-Ladies Global</title><link>https://--rladies-dev.netlify.app/news/2020-11-23-reduced-service-note/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://--rladies-dev.netlify.app/news/2020-11-23-reduced-service-note/</guid><description>This year has been and continues to be a challenging year for many, if not all, of us.
We have needed to make some adjustments in our personal lives and as R-Ladies is a volunteer run organisation we also needed to make some changes in the work we do at R-Ladies Global.
Since the coronavirus pandemic began, we have added new infrastructure for online meetups via Calendly, Zoom and a YouTube channel, along with guides and training for organizers.</description></item><item><title>#BlackLivesMatter: A joint statement by Forwards and R-Ladies</title><link>https://--rladies-dev.netlify.app/news/2020-06-06-blm/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://--rladies-dev.netlify.app/news/2020-06-06-blm/</guid><description>As organizations committed to broadening diversity and inclusion in our community, we stand with #BlackLivesMatter and join those who demand justice for systemic oppression. Pervasive racism negatively impacts the participation of Black people in society. The current events in the USA echo what has happened and continues to happen to minoritised people across the world. We are aggregating resources and are taking deliberate actions to amplify the voices of Black, Indigenous and People of Color in the R community now and moving forward.</description></item><item><title>Gabriela de Queiroz steps down from the R-Ladies Global Leadership Team</title><link>https://--rladies-dev.netlify.app/news/2019-12-18-gdq-departure/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://--rladies-dev.netlify.app/news/2019-12-18-gdq-departure/</guid><description>R-Ladies started out as a meetup group in San Francisco, when Gabriela de Queiroz founded the first chapter and organised the first event in 2012. Following this example, three further groups started out over the next three years. Shortly after the useR! conference in 2016, where Gabriela and other organisers met in person, the R-Ladies Global organisation was co-founded by several active community members.
Since then, the number of R-Ladies chapters has grown massively and rapidly.</description></item><item><title>R-Ladies Global's response to the DataCamp Assessment Report</title><link>https://--rladies-dev.netlify.app/news/2019-10-22-datacamp-third-party-review/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://--rladies-dev.netlify.app/news/2019-10-22-datacamp-third-party-review/</guid><description>DataCamp&amp;rsquo;s CEO Jonathan Cornelissen sexually assaulted an employee by making &amp;ldquo;uninvited physical contact&amp;rdquo; in October 2017. This became public in April 2019, after which we released a statement on our blog. For a comprehensive account of events, please see this article by Davey Alba for BuzzFeed News published in May 2019. DataCamp commissioned a third-party review which has now been released. This blogpost is to add some clarification around references to R-Ladies made in that report.</description></item><item><title>R-Ladies Global's disapproval of DataCamp</title><link>https://--rladies-dev.netlify.app/news/2019-04-08-statement-about-datacamp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://--rladies-dev.netlify.app/news/2019-04-08-statement-about-datacamp/</guid><description>This blog post is a slightly extended version of the official statement the R-Ladies Global organization made via Twitter, in a form that is easier to share. The views expressed here are the views of the R-Ladies Global Team signing at the end of this post and do not represent the R-Ladies community at large.
Why we condemn DataCamp&amp;rsquo;s handling of sexual assault We are very disappointed by the way DataCamp handled the sexual assault of an employee by a C-level executive.</description></item></channel></rss>