<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>News from the Global Team on R-Ladies Global</title><link>https://rladies.org/news/</link><description>Recent content in News from the Global Team on R-Ladies Global</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://rladies.org/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>R-Ladies is rebranding to R-Ladies+</title><link>https://rladies.org/news/2025/announcement/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rladies.org/news/2025/announcement/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;figure class="figure">
 &lt;img class="figure-img img-fluid rounded" 
 src="rladiesplus.png" 
 alt="Muted rainbow background with R-Ladies&amp;#43; in white large font and Welcomes You underneath in white font with pink background.">
 &lt;figcaption class="figure-caption">
 Muted rainbow background with R-Ladies+ in white large font and Welcomes You underneath in white font with pink background.
 &lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rebranding Call For Proposal</title><link>https://rladies.org/news/2025/cfp/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rladies.org/news/2025/cfp/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;figure class="figure">
 &lt;img class="figure-img img-fluid rounded" 
 src="cfp.png" 
 alt="Colors fade blue to violet left to right with white box in the middle that says Call for Proposal Rebranding R-Ladies to R-Ladies&amp;#43;; image of laptop adjacent.">
 &lt;figcaption class="figure-caption">
 Colors fade blue to violet left to right with white box in the middle that says Call for Proposal Rebranding R-Ladies to R-Ladies+; image of laptop adjacent.
 &lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>We're Launching the R-Ladies Rotating Curation Account on Bluesky!</title><link>https://rladies.org/news/2025/relaunch/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rladies.org/news/2025/relaunch/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re looking for curators for the We Are R-Ladies Bluesky account!</description></item><item><title>We're Relaunching the R-Ladies Abstract Review System!</title><link>https://rladies.org/news/2025/abstract-review-relaunch/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rladies.org/news/2025/abstract-review-relaunch/</guid><description>Supporting Aspiring Speakers in the R Community!</description></item><item><title>Volunteer as an R-Ladies Abstract Reviewer!</title><link>https://rladies.org/news/2025/abstract-review/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rladies.org/news/2025/abstract-review/</guid><description>Volunteer as an R-Ladies Abstract Reviewer to support diversity in tech!</description></item><item><title>Welcome to the Global Team</title><link>https://rladies.org/news/2024/welcome-global-team/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rladies.org/news/2024/welcome-global-team/</guid><description>R-Ladies Global Team has 15 new members!</description></item><item><title>R-Ladies &amp; Posit Cloud</title><link>https://rladies.org/news/2023/posit-cloud/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rladies.org/news/2023/posit-cloud/</guid><description>R-Ladies now has a Posit Cloud account available for R-Ladies meet-ups.</description></item><item><title>Mastodon: Meet the R-Ladies!</title><link>https://rladies.org/news/2023/mastodon-meet-the-r-ladies/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rladies.org/news/2023/mastodon-meet-the-r-ladies/</guid><description>R-Ladies are on mastodon&amp;rsquo;s Hackyderm server! Follow us at &lt;a href="https://hachyderm.io/@RLadiesGlobal">hachyderm.io/@RLadiesGlobal&lt;/a>!</description></item><item><title>R-Ladies Global and R-Ladies Chicago Reception at Posit Conf</title><link>https://rladies.org/news/2023/positconf-chicago-meetup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rladies.org/news/2023/positconf-chicago-meetup/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;figure class="figure">
 &lt;img class="figure-img img-fluid rounded" 
 src="posit-conf.jpg" 
 alt="">
 &lt;figcaption class="figure-caption">
 
 &lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Photo captured at the conclusion of the Question and Answer session of the reception. Alt text: R-Ladies community members gathered in a room of the Hyatt in Chicago, with rows of individuals standing, kneeling, and sitting.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Global Team Recruiting</title><link>https://rladies.org/news/2023/global-team-recruiting/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rladies.org/news/2023/global-team-recruiting/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;figure class="figure">
 &lt;img class="figure-img img-fluid rounded" 
 src="images/hannah-busing-Zyx1bK9mqmA-unsplash.jpg" 
 alt="hands">
 &lt;figcaption class="figure-caption">
 hands
 &lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Photo by &lt;a href="https://unsplash.com/@hannahbusing?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Hannah Busing&lt;/a> on &lt;a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/Zyx1bK9mqmA?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Unsplash&lt;/a>.
Alt text: Image of arms and hands of women wearing colorful sweaters in a circle with hands piled together.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="tl-dr">TL; DR&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The R-Ladies Global Team is recruiting new members!
Please fill &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1OZB6eVrsocvRyqD-ec5ui69SfXuOR8AZ_L-33B2d5yM/edit?pli=1">this form&lt;/a> to submit yourself for consideration.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>New R-Ladies Website</title><link>https://rladies.org/news/2023/02-22-new-r-ladies-website/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rladies.org/news/2023/02-22-new-r-ladies-website/</guid><description>&lt;hr>
&lt;p>There were some key issues we wanted to resolve with our webpage, that we could not easily maintain with the Wordpress site we had going:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Multilingual website: This is not the easiest to maintain with Wordpress&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Very slow directory: The database was just too slow and heavy, page loading time was horrible&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Integrate the blog into the website: The blog was a Blogdown site maintained through Github and Netlify&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Easier long-term maintenance and collaboration: Wordpress would require making a user for every person that wanted to contribute to the site
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Changing to something hosted on GitHub would mean easier community help and collaboration&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="history">History&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The work already started in 2019, with Bea Hernandez, Daloha Rodríguez-Molina and Maëlle Salmon.
The initial work was in making a &lt;a href="https://bookdown.org/yihui/blogdown/">blogdown&lt;/a> website, which utilises &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/">Hugo&lt;/a> and R markdown integration.
It was a natural place to start porting our Wordpress site into something more common to use in our community.
Additionally, the Wordpress site was requiring more and more maintenance, and in particular our &lt;a href="https://www.rladies.org/directory/">R-Ladies directory&lt;/a> was so slow we were getting reports of people not using it because the loading time of the page was so long!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In 2020, I (Athanasia Mowinckel) was on-boarded to the website team, initially to maintain the Wordpress site while the new Hugo site was being built.
After just a little while, I also started working on the blogdown site.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In mid-2020 we decided that the webpage was better served as a pure Hugo site, not as blogdown.
At that point, it was due to some Hugo features not existing in Blogdown (yet) that we wanted to utilise for the website.
These were settings for multi-lingual websites we really wanted to take advantage of.
At this point, I realised I was heavily invested in getting all the Hugo backbone working for R-Ladies, and that would mean creating our own custom theme, rather than something pre-made.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then Covid hit, and we all &lt;a href="https://www.rladies.org/news/2020-11-23-reduced-service-note/">felt the stress of that period&lt;/a>.
Development went slow, and things dragged out.
Thankfully, the Leadership contacted me and asked if I needed help to get the last pieces in place, and that we could set aside a little budget to hire help for the javascript pieces I was struggling with.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We &lt;a href="https://rladies.org/news/2022-03-28-request-for-proposal-javascript-development/">announced&lt;/a> the need, and hired &lt;a href="https://github.com/benubah">Ben Ubah&lt;/a> to help me get the last crucial pieces in place. Finally, we were nearing completion!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="release--new-features">Release &amp;amp; new features!&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We have now released the new website and are thrilled about how it works so far!
The theme is well suited to us, and the content is much easier to deal with now that we can collaborate through GitHub.
It&amp;rsquo;s also made it possible to integrate the website with certain other automatic pipelines, which enables us to have a couple of new features to the website from before!&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.rladies.org/activities/events/">Events page&lt;/a> with a calendar of R-Ladies events: These are fetched daily from meetup through their API&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.rladies.org/directory/">Directory page&lt;/a> which is actually fast!: Updated and maintained in another private repository with Airtable integration&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.rladies.org/blog/">Blog&lt;/a> where we welcome contributing posts and cross-posts: We&amp;rsquo;d love to see the blog revived and used by our community to show their skills and fun things they are doing with R!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.rladies.org/news/">News page&lt;/a> where the R-Ladies Global team can announce important notices about the global governance of our community&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>And more!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="future-work--call-for-community-help">Future work &amp;amp; call for community help&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There are still some things we are working on in the background, that we hope will improve the experience of our website, and also fulfil obligations we have promised previously.
We have a &lt;a href="https://github.com/rladies/rladies.github.io/wiki">website wiki&lt;/a> with more information about the setup of the website, and how people can contribute to the site.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="multilingual-webpage">Multilingual webpage&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We have set the website up to be multilingual, and have some development content for French, Spanish and Portuguese.
But, there is still a long way to go before we get to a point where these languages are well enough translated and enough content has been translated, for the language to be released in the production website.
Also, we are assuming that once we start having more translated content, we will see areas where the code needs fixing for proper multilingual support.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We hope with community help we can make an effort to cover the major languages used by our community.
The website wiki has its own section for &lt;a href="https://github.com/rladies/rladies.github.io/wiki/Adding-a-new-language">contributing site language translations&lt;/a>.
It likely needs work so it is more explicit on what the needs are, but we hope it provide a starting guide.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="directory-improvements">Directory improvements&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="updating-entries">Updating entries&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The directory has been ported from Wordpress with some rather elaborate and hacky scripts to get the content working for our new website.
This means, that for quite a lot of the entries, the content looks weird and out of place on the new website.
The best way to update your own entry in the directory, is to locate your entry and fill out the &lt;a href="https://airtable.com/shr54Z3BqfRJqypZ7">form&lt;/a> for updating the directory.
This way, we can create a better and more unified directory for all!&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="better-search--filtering">Better search / filtering&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Currently, we are using a fuzzy search for the directory.
While this does help somewhat, it can give odd results and it can be hard to find exactly what you are after.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are working on making better search and filtering functions for the directory, and if you have suggestions of how you would like to search it, we &lt;a href="https://github.com/rladies/rladies.github.io/issues">value your input&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="adding-new-pages">Adding new pages&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>There are quite some pages we are eager to start work on, so we can provide the best information available to our community and Funders.
We promised certain resources in our &lt;a href="https://rladies.org/news/2020-06-06-blm/">BML&lt;/a> statement, and we are keenly aware that we have yet to fulfil this.
Also, we know that our funders regularly want summaries of our activities, and we want to make a page dedicated to this type of information.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If there are pages you feel should exist, &lt;a href="https://github.com/rladies/rladies.github.io/issues">please do let us know&lt;/a> and we will consider your proposals.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="final-thoughts-from-the-main-developer">Final thoughts from the main developer&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It has been an amazing journey for me to work on this website.
I&amp;rsquo;ve learned so much, and I am thrilled to finally see it go &amp;ldquo;live&amp;rdquo;.
I look forward to the continued development, and we will be announcing the need for new website team members in not too long, to help me with the translation efforts, in revitalising the blog and in taking over the general maintenance of the new website.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>slug: &amp;ldquo;new-r-ladies-website&amp;rdquo;
aliases:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&amp;lsquo;/news/2023-02-22-new-r-ladies-website&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>We are thrilled to announce the release of our new R-Ladies website!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been a long journey, with many people involved, and we are happy to be able to finally share with you this new site and some new content.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Global Leadership Team Transition</title><link>https://rladies.org/news/2022/global-leadership-team-transition/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rladies.org/news/2022/global-leadership-team-transition/</guid><description>&lt;p>R-Ladies first began as a meet-up in 2012, and became a global organization in 2016.
Since inception, the R-Ladies Global organization has been run on 100% volunteer effort from individuals and chapters throughout the world.
The organization is built upon layers of support - &lt;a href="https://rladies.org/about-us/team/">the global leadership team, the broader global team&lt;/a>, local chapter organizers, and community members - all who donate their time and effort to sustain the mission of promoting gender diversity in the R community.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Request for Proposal - Javascript Development (Contract Work)</title><link>https://rladies.org/news/2022/request-for-proposal-javascript-development/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rladies.org/news/2022/request-for-proposal-javascript-development/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>The R-Ladies global organization wants to implement some new functionalities (using Javascript) for a re-implementation of their website, whose source code may be found on &lt;a href="https://github.com/rladies/website">GitHub&lt;/a>.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>R-Ladies would like to invite you to prepare a proposal to accomplish the above task that includes timeline, cost, and deliverables. The following RFP includes a background of our organization and describes the purpose of the redesign, its desired functionality, and specific requests relating to the proposal. We understand that details may be subject to change upon vendor recommendation and/ or research of more optimal solutions. In your proposal, please feel free to suggest alternatives where noted.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reduced Service Mode for R-Ladies Global</title><link>https://rladies.org/news/2020/reduced-service-note/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rladies.org/news/2020/reduced-service-note/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year has been and continues to be a challenging year for many, if not all, of us.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have needed to make some adjustments in our personal lives and as R-Ladies is a volunteer run organisation we also needed to make some changes in the work we do at R-Ladies Global.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#BlackLivesMatter: A joint statement by Forwards and R-Ladies</title><link>https://rladies.org/news/2020/blm/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rladies.org/news/2020/blm/</guid><description>&lt;p>As organizations committed to broadening diversity and inclusion in our community, we stand with #BlackLivesMatter and join those who demand justice for systemic oppression. Pervasive racism negatively impacts the participation of Black people in society. The current events in the USA echo what has happened and continues to happen to minoritised people across the world. We are aggregating resources and are taking deliberate actions to amplify the voices of Black, Indigenous and People of Color in the R community now and moving forward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gabriela de Queiroz steps down from the R-Ladies Global Leadership Team</title><link>https://rladies.org/news/2019/gdq-departure/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rladies.org/news/2019/gdq-departure/</guid><description>&lt;p>R-Ladies started out as a meetup group in San Francisco, when Gabriela de Queiroz founded the first chapter and organised the first event in 2012. Following this example, three further groups started out over the next three years. Shortly after the useR! conference in 2016, where Gabriela and other organisers met in person, the R-Ladies Global organisation was co-founded by several active community members.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>R-Ladies Global's response to the DataCamp Assessment Report</title><link>https://rladies.org/news/2019/datacamp-third-party-review/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rladies.org/news/2019/datacamp-third-party-review/</guid><description>&lt;p>DataCamp&amp;rsquo;s CEO Jonathan Cornelissen sexually assaulted an employee by making &lt;a href="https://www.datacamp.com/community/blog/note-to-our-community">&amp;ldquo;uninvited physical contact&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a> in October 2017. This became public in April 2019, after which we released a statement on our &lt;a href="https://blog.rladies.org/post/statement-about-datacamp/">blog&lt;/a>. For a comprehensive account of events, please see this article by &lt;a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/daveyalba/datacamp-sexual-harassment-metoo-tech-startup">Davey Alba for BuzzFeed News&lt;/a> published in May 2019. DataCamp commissioned a third-party review which has now been &lt;a href="https://assets.datacamp.com/working-ideal-independent-third-party-review-of-datacamp.pdf">released&lt;/a>. This blogpost is to add some clarification around references to R-Ladies made in that report.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>R-Ladies Global's disapproval of DataCamp</title><link>https://rladies.org/news/2019/statement-about-datacamp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rladies.org/news/2019/statement-about-datacamp/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This blog post is a slightly extended version of the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RLadiesGlobal/status/1114507499728769024">official statement the R-Ladies Global organization made via Twitter&lt;/a>, in a form that is easier to share. The views expressed here are the views of the R-Ladies Global Team signing at the end of this post and do not represent the R-Ladies community at large.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>