<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About-Uses on R-Ladies Global</title><link>https://rladies.org/about-us/</link><description>Recent content in About-Uses on R-Ladies Global</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://rladies.org/about-us/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Get Involved</title><link>https://rladies.org/about-us/involved/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rladies.org/about-us/involved/</guid><description>&lt;center>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://rladies.org/about-us/involved/img/rladies-help.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;/center>
&lt;p>We welcome your contributions, below are handful of ideas ðŸ’œ&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="-getting-started">ðŸ Getting started&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Update &lt;a href="https://rladies.org/directory/">R-Ladies directory&lt;/a> with your details&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Join our &lt;a href="https://rladies.org/form/community-slack">community slack&lt;/a> channel&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Follow us over &lt;a href="https://hachyderm.io/@RLadiesGlobal">social media&lt;/a>. Periodically we share about upcoming activities&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Join your regional &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/pro/rladies/">R-Ladies chapter&lt;/a> or the remote chapter, perfect space to connect with likeminded individuals&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Attend the online/in-person events. The details for upcoming events could be found over slack channels/ social media&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Content along with recordings for our past events are openly accessible over &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@RLadiesGlobal">YouTube&lt;/a> channel, reach out to speakers that you like and let them know that you appreciate their content&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="always-room-for-more">ðŸ’¡Always room for more&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Propose a talk for a meetup/event/conference&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Become a chapter organizer by volunteering with your local chapter or starting your own (please get in touch via &lt;a href="mailto:chapters@rladies.org">chapters@rladies.org&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Contribute a blog post to the &lt;a href="https://rladies.org/">website&lt;/a>, we are always here to help.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="-above-and-beyond">ðŸ¤ Above and beyond&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Join the &lt;a href="https://rladies.org/about-us/global-team/">global team&lt;/a>, help us create a diverse space&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create issues or PR(s) over &lt;a href="https://github.com/rladies">GitHub&lt;/a> for our &lt;a href="https://github.com/rladies/rladies.github.io">website&lt;/a> &amp;amp; &lt;a href="https://github.com/rladies/rladiesguide">guide&lt;/a> when you encounter sections which could be improved&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Contribute to community discussion and share your thoughts&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support your local chapters with venue space and funding for food and beverages&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support our infrastructure and behind-the-scenes operations. We appreciate your donations via &lt;a href="https://www.paypal.com/donate/?hosted_button_id=VB4EK67MJ373E">PayPal&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>History</title><link>https://rladies.org/about-us/history/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rladies.org/about-us/history/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://rladies.org/united-states-rladies/name/gabriela-de-queiroz/">Gabriela de Queiroz&lt;/a> founded R-Ladies on October 1, 2012. She wanted to give back to the community after going to several meetups and learning a lot for free.
The first meetup was held in San Francisco, California (United States).
In the following years, two more R-Ladies chapters started around the globe: Twin Cities and Taipei.
R-Ladies London was the fourth chapter, which launched in March 2016. Although each chapter started working independently, the need for high-level coordination and support became evident at useR! 2016 where the San Francisco and London chapters met.
After some initial brainstorming during the useR! 2016 conference, Gabriela de Queiroz and Erin LeDell from R-Ladies San Francisco and Chiin-Rui Tan, Alice Daish, Hannah Frick, Rachel Kirkham, and Claudia Vitolo from R-Ladies London, as well as Heather Turner, teamed up to apply for an R-Consortium &lt;a href="https://github.com/rladies/global/blob/master/rconsortium/FINAL%20-%20201607-%20rconsortiumproposalr-ladiesalignmentandglobalexpansion-july2016.pdf">grant to support and encourage the global expansion of the R-Ladies organisation&lt;/a>.
R-Ladies Global was born, and the grant was awarded in September 2016.
Since then R-Ladies has grown to &lt;a href="https://benubah.github.io/r-community-explorer/rladies.html">200+ chapters across 60+ countries with 100,000+ members&lt;/a>, thanks to our amazing organisers and R-Ladies who helped build and maintain our official website (&lt;a href="https://rladies.org/">rladies.org&lt;/a>), engage with the larger community via social media (&lt;a href="https://bsky.app/profile/rladies.org">@RLadiesGlobal&lt;/a>) and help each-other every day in millions of different ways.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Meet the global team</title><link>https://rladies.org/about-us/global-team/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rladies.org/about-us/global-team/</guid><description>&lt;p>R-ladies Global is run by a volunteer group with designated responsibilities within the organisation.
The leadership team has an overarching role, making sure the organisation is well-structured, keeps promises made to sponsors and members, and directs the evolution of R-ladies as a whole.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mission</title><link>https://rladies.org/about-us/mission/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rladies.org/about-us/mission/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>R-LADIES IS A WORLDWIDE ORGANIZATION WHOSE MISSION IS TO PROMOTE GENDER DIVERSITY IN THE R COMMUNITY.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The R community suffers from an under-representation of minority genders (including but not limited to cis/trans women, trans men, non-binary, genderqueer, agender) in every role and area of participation, whether as leaders, package developers, conference speakers, conference participants, educators, or users (&lt;a href="https://forwards.github.io/data.html">see recent stats&lt;/a>).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>