<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About-us on R-Ladies Global</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/about-us/</link><description>Recent content in About-us on R-Ladies Global</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://www.rladies.org/about-us/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Get Involved</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/about-us/involved/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/about-us/involved/</guid><description>Support your local chapters with venue space and funding for food and beverages. Support your local R-Ladies speakers by inviting them to talk – no excuses for unequal conference speaker ratios. Use the R-Ladies directory. Join the R-Ladies directory . Encourage coding women to be part of R-Ladies. Share code (R-Ladies Global Github). Inspire and support others. Join the community slack. Teach. Blog. Tweet, Retweet and follow @RLadiesGlobal and R-Ladies chapter accounts.</description></item><item><title>History</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/about-us/history/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/about-us/history/</guid><description>Gabriela de Queiroz founded R-Ladies on October 1, 2012. She wanted to give back to the community after going to several meetups and learning a lot for free. The first meetup was placed in San Francisco, California (United States). In the following years two more R-Ladies chapters started around the globe: Twin Cities and Taipei. R-Ladies London was the fourth chapter, which launched in March 2016. Although each chapter started working independently, the need for high-level coordination and support became evident at useR!</description></item><item><title>Meet the global team</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/about-us/global-team/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/about-us/global-team/</guid><description>R-ladies Global is run by a volunteer group with designated responsibilities within the organisation. The leadership team has an overarching role, making sure the organisation is well-structured, keeps promises made to sponsors and members, and directs the evolution of R-ladies as a whole.</description></item><item><title>Mission</title><link>https://www.rladies.org/about-us/mission/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rladies.org/about-us/mission/</guid><description>R-LADIES IS A WORLDWIDE ORGANIZATION WHOSE MISSION IS TO PROMOTE GENDER DIVERSITY IN THE R COMMUNITY.
The R community suffers from an under-representation of minority genders (including but not limited to cis/trans women, trans men, non-binary, genderqueer, agender) in every role and area of participation, whether as leaders, package developers, conference speakers, conference participants, educators, or users (see recent stats).
As a diversity initiative, the mission of R-Ladies is to achieve proportionate representation by encouraging, inspiring, and empowering people of genders currently under-represented in the R community.</description></item></channel></rss>