<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>community on R-Ladies Global</title><link>https://rladies.org/tags/community/</link><description>Recent content in community on R-Ladies Global</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rladies.org/tags/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Curating for @WeAreRLadies on Twitter</title><link>https://rladies.org/blog/2021-09-23-curating-for-wearerladies-on-twitter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rladies.org/blog/2021-09-23-curating-for-wearerladies-on-twitter/</guid><description>Figure 1: Photo by Arno Smit on Unsplash (https://unsplash.com/photos/iI72r3gSwWY) This post was originally published on Shannon Pileggi’s personal blog.
TL; DR In February 2021 I tweeted to a daunting &amp;gt;20k followers by curating for @WeAreLadies on Twitter. This was great opportunity to share knowledge, interact with others, and learn something in return, ultimately cultivating new connections and collaborations. From preparation to fruition, I hope this post helps you confidently enroll as a curator!</description></item><item><title>The R-Ladies Mentoring Program: R-Ladies Cotonou journey</title><link>https://rladies.org/blog/2021-02-04-cotonout_mentoring/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rladies.org/blog/2021-02-04-cotonout_mentoring/</guid><description>We are very happy to provide you this blog article in different languages, English, French and Spanish. If you would like to know more about how to contribute to the R-Ladies Blog in general or would like to recommend anything, please reach out to us with an e-mail at christin@rladies.org.
How it all started …? 🤔 R-Ladies Cotonou is a local chapter of R-Ladies Global located in Cotonou, Benin (West Africa).</description></item><item><title>Reduced Service Mode for R-Ladies Global</title><link>https://rladies.org/news/2020-11-23-reduced-service-note/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rladies.org/news/2020-11-23-reduced-service-note/</guid><description>This year has been and continues to be a challenging year for many, if not all, of us.
We have needed to make some adjustments in our personal lives and as R-Ladies is a volunteer run organisation we also needed to make some changes in the work we do at R-Ladies Global.
Since the coronavirus pandemic began, we have added new infrastructure for online meetups via Calendly, Zoom and a YouTube channel, along with guides and training for organizers.</description></item><item><title>R-Ladies Infrastructure for Online Meetups</title><link>https://rladies.org/blog/2020-04-24-online-meetups/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rladies.org/blog/2020-04-24-online-meetups/</guid><description>Our chapters have cancelled in-person meetups due to the corona virus pandemic. However, we want our members to be able to stay connected and still share their latest R-related discoveries and journeys. To support our chapter organisers in moving their events online, we decided to provide them with video conferencing infrastructure.
Our network has grown to over 160 chapters worldwide so we were wondering how many meeting rooms we would need.</description></item><item><title>Gabriela de Queiroz steps down from the R-Ladies Global Leadership Team</title><link>https://rladies.org/news/2019-12-18-gdq-departure/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rladies.org/news/2019-12-18-gdq-departure/</guid><description>R-Ladies started out as a meetup group in San Francisco, when Gabriela de Queiroz founded the first chapter and organised the first event in 2012. Following this example, three further groups started out over the next three years. Shortly after the useR! conference in 2016, where Gabriela and other organisers met in person, the R-Ladies Global organisation was co-founded by several active community members.
Since then, the number of R-Ladies chapters has grown massively and rapidly.</description></item><item><title>R-Ladies Global's response to the DataCamp Assessment Report</title><link>https://rladies.org/news/2019-10-22-datacamp-third-party-review/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rladies.org/news/2019-10-22-datacamp-third-party-review/</guid><description>DataCamp&amp;rsquo;s CEO Jonathan Cornelissen sexually assaulted an employee by making &amp;ldquo;uninvited physical contact&amp;rdquo; in October 2017. This became public in April 2019, after which we released a statement on our blog. For a comprehensive account of events, please see this article by Davey Alba for BuzzFeed News published in May 2019. DataCamp commissioned a third-party review which has now been released. This blogpost is to add some clarification around references to R-Ladies made in that report.</description></item><item><title>R-Ladies Global's disapproval of DataCamp</title><link>https://rladies.org/news/2019-04-08-statement-about-datacamp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rladies.org/news/2019-04-08-statement-about-datacamp/</guid><description>This blog post is a slightly extended version of the official statement the R-Ladies Global organization made via Twitter, in a form that is easier to share. The views expressed here are the views of the R-Ladies Global Team signing at the end of this post and do not represent the R-Ladies community at large.
Why we condemn DataCamp&amp;rsquo;s handling of sexual assault We are very disappointed by the way DataCamp handled the sexual assault of an employee by a C-level executive.</description></item></channel></rss>