<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R-Ladies</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on R-Ladies</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>3. Behind the scenes of R-Ladies IWD2018 Twitter action!</title>
      <link>/post/conclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/conclusion/</guid>
      <description>As told by Page and Sheila On March the 8th, International Women’s Day, we ran a continuous feed of awesome R-Ladies profiles from our directory via [@rladies_iwd2018](https://twitter.com/rladies_iwd2018). It was a blast! And a lot of team work too! To round out our three-part blog series of the IWD Directory campaign, we’ll discuss topics related to privacy law, contact information collection and the future of our R-Ladies directory project. You can also read the Part 1 and Part 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2. Behind the scenes of R-Ladies IWD2018 Twitter action!</title>
      <link>/post/deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/deployment/</guid>
      <description>As told by Kelly O’Briant On March the 8th, International Women’s Day, we ran a continuous feed of awesome R-Ladies profiles from our directory via @rladies_iwd2018. It was a blast! And a lot of team work too! In this blog post, we’ll cover the deployment and monitoring stages of our project. You can also read the Part 1.
 Recap The great part about being put in charge of deploying a project, is that all the hard work is mostly done already!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1. Behind the scenes of R-Ladies IWD2018 Twitter action!</title>
      <link>/post/ideation_and_creation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ideation_and_creation/</guid>
      <description>As told by Maëlle Salmon with notes from Bea Hernández On March the 8th, International Women’s Day, we ran a continuous feed of awesome R-Ladies profiles from our directory via @rladies_iwd2018. It was a blast! And a lot of team work too! In this blog post, we’ll explain how we designed and completed our Twitter action.
 An idea sown on IWD2017! Last year on International Women’s day, R-Ladies ally David Robinson promoted Twitter accounts of female data scientists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>History</title>
      <link>/post/history/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/history/</guid>
      <description>Gabriela de Queiroz founded R-Ladies on October 1, 2012. She wanted to give back to the community after going to several meetups and learning a lot for free. The first meetup was placed in San Francisco, California (United States).
In the following years two more R-Ladies chapters started around the globe: Twin Cities and Taipei. R-Ladies London was the fourth chapter, which launched in March 2016. Although each chapter started working independently, the need for high-level coordination and support became evident at useR!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>