<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Iwd on R-Ladies</title>
    <link>/tags/iwd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Iwd on R-Ladies</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/iwd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>4. Behind the scenes of R-Ladies IWD2018 Twitter action!</title>
      <link>/post/rladies_tweets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/rladies_tweets/</guid>
      <description>As told by Daloha Rodríguez-Molina, with help from Maëlle Salmon R-Ladies is a global organization that promotes diversity in the R community. One way to do this is by raising the visibility of women and other underrepresented genders1 in tech, especially those who are R users, or developers.
1 (cis/trans women, trans men, non-binary, genderqueer, agender, or other).
The R-Ladies Global Team instigated a unique initiative to increase female visibility in tech, as part of the 2018 International Women’s Day celebration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3. Behind the scenes of R-Ladies IWD2018 Twitter action!</title>
      <link>/post/conclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/conclusion/</guid>
      <description>As told by Page and Sheila On March the 8th, International Women’s Day, we ran a continuous feed of awesome R-Ladies profiles from our directory via [@rladies_iwd2018](https://twitter.com/rladies_iwd2018). It was a blast! And a lot of team work too! To round out our three-part blog series of the IWD Directory campaign, we’ll discuss topics related to privacy law, contact information collection and the future of our R-Ladies directory project. You can also read the Part 1 and Part 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2. Behind the scenes of R-Ladies IWD2018 Twitter action!</title>
      <link>/post/deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/deployment/</guid>
      <description>As told by Kelly O’Briant On March the 8th, International Women’s Day, we ran a continuous feed of awesome R-Ladies profiles from our directory via @rladies_iwd2018. It was a blast! And a lot of team work too! In this blog post, we’ll cover the deployment and monitoring stages of our project. You can also read the Part 1.
 Recap The great part about being put in charge of deploying a project, is that all the hard work is mostly done already!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1. Behind the scenes of R-Ladies IWD2018 Twitter action!</title>
      <link>/post/ideation_and_creation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ideation_and_creation/</guid>
      <description>As told by Maëlle Salmon with notes from Bea Hernández On March the 8th, International Women’s Day, we ran a continuous feed of awesome R-Ladies profiles from our directory via @rladies_iwd2018. It was a blast! And a lot of team work too! In this blog post, we’ll explain how we designed and completed our Twitter action.
 An idea sown on IWD2017! Last year on International Women’s day, R-Ladies ally David Robinson promoted Twitter accounts of female data scientists.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>